Zhike(Kyle) Chen

Email: zk.chen007@gmail.com

Phone/WhatsApp: (65) 85751796

GitHub: kk17

Summary

Experience with big data technologies: Hadoop MapReduce, Spark, Hive, NoSQL, relational database, etc. Experience with AWS EMR cloud platforms. Experience in developing distributed web-system using microservice architecture. Familiar with service build, deploy, and release process using GitLab CI. Proficient with Java, Python, Spring, MySQL, Docker, GitLab CI, etc.; Familiar with Scala, NoSQL, GO, Node.js, etc.

Work Experience

ADVANCEAI SINGAPORE, DATA ENGINEER TEAM

Senior Data Engineer Apr. 2018 - Present

As a Senior Data Engineer in the Data Engineer Team, I participated in the designing, building, and maintaining our growing big data platform using the big data stack such as Hadoop, Spark, AWS EMR, AWS S3, Hive, Airflow, etc.

- Set up and maintain a data processing and data warehouse environment using AWS EMR and S3.
- Implement ETL data pipelines for the data processing from different upstream servers and sources, such as MySQL database, MongoDB, log files, etc.
- Migrated the ETL pipelines form Jenkins to Airflow. Pipelines became more easily to be scheduled, managed, monitored in one place with easy access to a comprehensive view of the status.
- Continually optimize the ETL pipelines, improve the efficiency and reduce the overall execution time.
- Analyze data in the warehouse and created dashboards using PySpark, JupyterHub, and Superset. Product managers and others can understand our business better.
- Deployed and maintained Spark Thrift Server, implement custom authentication and authorization for it. Business Analysts and Data Scientists can write SQL statements to analyze data. Significantly increased the ease of use without loss of security.
- Build and maintain some infrastructure services of our data platform in a service mesh architecture.
- Explore/learn new technologies that can complement or replace our current stack to improve it.

NETEASE GUANGZHOU, CHINA, DEPARTMENT OF MAIL SERVICES

Senior Backend Developer Sep. 2015 - Mar. 2018 (2 years and 5 months)

As a Senior Backend Developer, I played the primary role in the development and maintenance of multi underlying basic services for our e-commerce platform using Spring Could Microservice architecture and also designed out automatic deployment system.

- Design, develop and maintain series of backend services including basic goods management, vendor management, event message, and other services using various technologies (Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, MyBaits, NoSQL, RabbitMQ, Solr, etc.)
- Built the automatically deployment solution for building and deploying our microservices based on the technical stack of GitLab Cl and Docker, Python, Go, Shell, etc. Significantly improved the efficiency of service deployment time.
- Refactored and migrated some exists services into Spring Could Microservice architecture. Services became more maintainable and suitable for rapid iterative development.
- Researched open-source application-notification-push solutions, selected the key solution, and modified source code to meet specific needs.
- Guided interns and other team members for analyzing and solving problems.

NETEASE HANGZHOU, CHINA, CLOUD MUSIC PRODUCT CENTER

Senior Java Backend Developer Jul. 2012 - Sep. 2015 (3 years and 2 months)

I joined the team at the very beginning as a Backend Developer, contributed to many service APIs for the NetEase Cloud Music multi-platform application.

- Designed, developed and maintained of services APIs, including user account, order, payment, radio program services APIs for client applications.
- Cooperated with client developers for debugging and testing application. Built an API test tool (wrote in Python) to simplify API tests and made tests more efficient.
- Communicated with Sonos developers, implemented the required web services APIs for integrating our product with Sonos HiFi System.

Education Background

• Jinan University GUANGZHOU, CHINA 2008-2012

Bachelor Of Computer Science And Technology